One forty-nine please.
一块四毛九
How much is the milk?
这牛奶多少钱？
Forty-nine pence.
四十九便士
Thank you.
谢谢
Too much. Much too much butter. - I like butter.
- 太多了，黄油抹太多了 - 我喜欢吃黄油
Milk’s gone up.
牛奶涨价了
49p a pint.
49便士一品脱了
Good grief! We’ll have to economise.
好伤心！看来我们要节衣缩食了
I suppose we could always sell the car. Or take in paying guests!
或许我们可以把车卖了 或者让做客的人付钱
Watch out. She’s on the prowl.
当心哦，她在伺机而动呢
Eat your egg.
吃你的鸡蛋吧
Goodness! There you are.
天呢！您在这儿呀
Yes. Here we are.
当然，我们在这儿
I don’t understand how it happened,
真不明白是怎么回事
how could she possibly have got out? It’s very very important -
她是怎么溜出去的？ 这件事非常重要
Please just make it really clear.
这件事一定要说清楚
Who’s on after you?
你后面是谁值班？
Beautiful day. Oh, you’ve made a start.
多美好的一天啊 噢，你已经准备开始了
Carol’s coming soon, I’ll get some bags.
卡萝尔马上就来了 我给你准备一些包装袋
Anything you want to go to Mark, I’ll bring up a suitcase for it.
如果有任何东西想要给马克 我会拿一个旅行箱来装
No no no no. The grey.
不不不，灰色这件
You sure?
你确定？
Yes. ...Definitely the grey.
那当然 当然是灰色这件
Righty ho.
真是保守派
Boss knows best.
一切老大说了算
Don’t let her take my paper away.
让她不要拿走我的报纸
Oh, I haven’t had a chance to look at that yet, dear.
噢，我还没来得及看那个报纸呢
Sorry.
抱歉
Atta-girl.
好姑娘
Damn.
该死
Blot it...Blot it..
抹掉，抹掉...
pardon.
您说什么？
Now look what you’ve done.
看看你干的好事
Are they to keep the loonies out or you in?
这些人是要把疯子赶出去 还是要把你关家里？
I’ll be off then.
我走了
Wear your scarf. There’s a chill out there.
戴围巾 外面挺冷的
Good morning Lady Thatcher.
早上好，撒切尔夫人
Are you alright? How are you feeling?
你还好吗？ 感觉如何？
I’m fine, thank you Susie.
我很好，谢谢你苏西
I’ve just been reading about the bombings.
我正在读爆炸袭击的报道
Yes. Frightful.
是啊，真可怕
Sorry.
对不起
These are the books for you to sign.
这些是需要您签名的书
I brought as many as I could find. Shall we go through your appointments?
我尽量把能找来的都拿来了 我们再一起看看行程预约表吧？
We said we’d go through them today.
我们说过今天要一起看看
Yes, of course, dear. Today.
当然，亲爱的，是今天
The invitation has come from Downing Street for the unveiling of your portrait.
唐宁街（英国首相府所在地）发来了 您的画像揭幕仪式的邀请函
I’ll put it on the mantelpiece, and there’s an invitation from Lord Armstrong for
我会把邀请函放在壁炉台上 阿姆斯特朗勋爵也发来邀请
lunch on the first Friday of next month.
请您下个月第一个星期五一起吃午餐
I said no because you’ve got a concert that afternoon but if you’d like to...
我回绝了因为您那个下午有一个音乐会 但是如果您想去...
It looks like a very interesting programme.
音乐会的节目单看上去很不错
What are they playing?
表演些什么？
I think they said Rogers and Hammerstein.
应该是罗杰斯和哈姆斯坦 （Richard Rodgers 和 Oscar Hammerstein II，著名美国歌曲作者组合）
Silly man.
笨家伙
He hasn’t got his scarf on.
他忘记戴围巾了
Did someone cover the butter?
有人把黄油盖起来了吗？
I’ll go.
我去
Leave it. Margaret-
- 算了吧 - 玛格丽特...
Good girl.
乖孩子
Tomorrow, no matter what they do, it’ll be business as usual.
明天不管他们要做什么 我们还是照常营业
Two of the small beef, Mr. Roberts.
两块小牛肉，罗伯茨先生
What is the life blood of any community? It’s business...
任何社会形式的血液是什么？ 是商业
Not just big business but small businesses, like mine.
不仅仅是大生意，还有小的 比如我的
Margaret! CUPS!
玛格丽特！拿杯子！
We on this island are strong. We’re self-reliant.
我们是强大的岛国人民 我们自给自足
Sometimes we’re plain bloody minded.
有时候，我们极度志同道合
But we also believe in helping each other.
我们也相信互助的道理
And I don’t mean by state hand-outs...
我并不是指政府的扶持...
Margaret, do you want to come to the pictures?
玛格丽特，想不想去看电影？
She can’t come, she’s got to study.
她不能去，她要学习
Miss Hoity Toity!
高傲的小姐~!
Never run with the crowd, Margaret. Go your own way.
永远不要随波逐流，玛格丽特 走自己的路
I’ve got a place at Oxford.
我被牛津大学录取了
Don’t let me down Margaret.
不要让我失望，玛格丽特
Mother?
妈妈？
My hands are still damp.
我手还是湿的
Margaret!CUPS!
玛格丽特！拿杯子！
They’re talking about you again.
他们又在聊起你了
What time is it?
几点了？
Sun’s not quite over the yard arm. Time for tea.
还未日上三竿 该喝茶了
What have you got on your head?
你到底在想什么呢？
Found it in the cupboard and thought bugger it, it’s Friday, why not fancy dress?
我在橱柜里找到的，就想穿穿看 今天礼拜五，干嘛不穿点好看衣服呢
You look ridiculous.
看上去笨死了
Bosslady no like?
老婆大人不喜欢？
No, Denis, Bosslady no like.
不，丹尼斯 老婆大人当然不喜欢
Can I suggest you remove the sticker from the back of your car.
我能不能建议您 把车背后的贴纸拿掉
xxx
抱歉我总是收现金的
Well then take the sticker off! I call that false advertising!
那就把贴纸拿掉啊！ 这是虚假信息！
xxx - I would say keep the change...
- 我还有别人叫车了... - 我本来想给你小费
but there isn’t any change.
现在什么都没有了
Hello June, any news? I’ve brought every bag I could find.
琼，有什么新消息吗？ 我把能找来的袋子都拿来了
Hello Ma.
妈，你好吗
Bloody taxi driver. Wouldn’t take my card.
该死的出租车司机 不刷卡
I said don’t have a sticker saying you take Visa and then insist on cash.
我就说你不能车上贴个标志说 可以刷卡，但结果要收现金
Can you believe it? I was rummaging around the bottom of my bag. He didn’t get a tip.
真不敢相信，我都把包翻了个底朝天 他一毛小费都没得
I didn’t know that you were dropping by today, dear.
我不知道你今天要过来啊，亲爱的
Yes, you said yesterday... You wanted to make a start on Dad’s things.
啊，你昨天说了... 你想要开始收拾爸爸的遗物
The cupboards? Then I can help you dress.
先收拾橱柜？ 我可以帮你穿戴一下
You’ve got Michael and-
迈克尔还有...
Jaqueline... Coming for dinner tonight.
杰奎琳... 他们今晚来吃晚饭
Of course.
噢当然
We’re having halibut.
我们晚上吃比目鱼
Oh God. Isn’t it terrible? They think it’s Al Quaida -
天哪，真是太可怕了 他们认为是基地组织干的...
It’ll be fine. Come on, get your head down, it’s ten to three, for God’s sake.
没事的，去睡一会儿吧 已经三点差10分了，天哪
At ten to three this morning an explosion...
今天凌晨2点50... 一场爆炸案...
extensively damaged the Grand Hotel in Brighton
造成了布莱顿旅馆的大面积毁损
scene of the Conservative Party conference.
那里正在举行保守党大会
Where the Prime Minister and a number of her cabinet were staying.
首相和她的一些内阁正下榻在这酒店
They escaped unhurt -
他们没有受伤
Five people have died, many others are injured, some critically.
造成5人死亡，多人受伤 有一些是重伤
The IRA have claimed responsibility.
爱尔兰共和军宣称对此次事件负责
We must release a statement, offering our condolences.
我们必须发布声明 表示慰问
I’m sure they’ve already-
他们肯定已经...
We must never, ever, ever give in to terrorists.
我们绝对，绝对，绝对 不能对恐怖分子投降
Good moring dear.
噢早上好亲爱的
Now ma, are we going long or just below the knee tonight?
妈，今晚是穿长裙，还是 只是膝盖下的就好了？
Oh, below the knee I should think.
噢，那就膝盖下的吧
No! Don’t move those. I haven’t finished sorting them.
不，别动那些！ 我还没有分类好
I hear you went out today...
听说你今天出门了...
You mustn’t go out on your own Mummy. We’ve talked about that.
妈，你不能一个人出门的 我们说好了的
There was no milk.
没有牛奶了
Call Robert he’ll get it for you if June’s not up-
给罗伯特打电话，他会给你买 如果琼还没有起床...
I am not for the knackers yet.
我还不是废物吧
Now take it easy, Margaret.
别这样，玛格丽特
No one is saying that.
没人这么说
If I can’t go out to buy a pint of milk then what is the world coming to.
如果我连一品脱牛奶都不能自己去买了 这世界会变成什么样啊
Really Carol...
我说真的，卡萝尔...
please don’t fuss about it.
别计较这个了
You’ve always been like this, fuss fuss fuss.
你总是这样，小题大作
You must find something better to do with your time.
你得找点其他事情做啊
It’s most unattractive in a woman.
女人这样最没吸引力了
When I was your age...
我想你这么大的时候...
the last thing I wanted to do was fuss around my mother.
最不愿意做的事 就是跟母亲斤斤计较
Four down, 9 letters.
下面第四行，九个字母的字
Something b something t something n...
空格b，空格t，空格n...
something something somthing... Refusal to change course-
空格空格空格... 意思是拒绝换题目
Obstinate.
Obstinate（顽固的）
Pearls. I’ll wear the pearls.
我想戴珍珠项链
There they are. My little twins.
真好，我的宝贝们
Thank you, dear.
谢谢亲爱的
It’s nearly all familiar faces, William, Michael and his lovely wife-
都是很熟悉的人 威廉，迈克尔，还有他妻子...
Jacqueline.
杰奎琳
And then there’s Peter, James R and James T and that very nice man-
然后还有彼得，詹姆斯・R 詹姆斯・T，还有那个很好的人...
Yes- we met last year.
是的 我们去年见过了
Yes I remember-
我记得
I think he’s bringing his new lady friend just to mix it up a bit.
我觉得他今天应该会带新的女伴来 调节调节气氛
We’re rather short on women - but I’m sure we’ll manage-
我们这里很缺女人 不过我肯定我们会改善...
I’ve always preferred the company of men-
我总是很喜欢与男性为伴
Ma?
妈？
Ah, Miss Roberts.
啊，罗伯茨小姐
Hoping to be chosen as our candidate for parliament.
希望能被选为国会候选人
Well I don’t like coalitions, never have...
我不喜欢联盟 从不...
Start on the outside and work your way in.
从外部包围开始 逐渐深入
Attlee has his sights set on the steel industry, you mark my words.
艾德利在钢铁工业方面很有远见 你记着我这句话
They’ll be nationalizing the bloody air next.
接下来是不是要把 该死的空气也收归国有了
Yes, hold your breath, sir, that’s government property!
那是啊，屏住呼吸吧 那可是政府财产！
So was your father a political man, too, Miss Roberts?
你的父亲也是从政的吗 罗伯茨小姐？
Oh, yes, to his core. And Mayor of Grantham.
是的，在他们那群人中 还是格兰瑟姆（英格兰林肯郡）的镇长
And a grocer as well!
还是个卖杂货的！
Yes.
是的
And did you help, in the... shop? - Oh, yes. It was a family business.
- 那么...你会在店里帮忙吗？ - 噢是的，算是家庭经营
A very good starting point for the political life, I’m sure.
我肯定这对于政客生活是个很好的开端
That and a degree from Oxford.
还包括一个牛津大学的学位
Whisky.
威士忌
What I do think is that a man should be encouraged to stand on his own two feet.
我坚信一个人应该 被鼓励自给自足
Yes we help people of course we help people. But for those that can do...
是的当然我们要互相帮助 但对于有能力的人
they must just get up and do.
他们必须站起来，做点什么
And if something’s wrong, they shouldn’t just whine about it...
如果有什么不顺心 也不应该只是发牢骚
they should get in there and DO something about it, change things.
他们应该有所作为 去改变现状
With all due respect, Miss Roberts, what may have served in Grantham-
我们很尊重你的意见，罗伯茨小姐 格兰瑟姆那边的管理方法...
Can serve very well for the people of Dartford too.
对达特佛德的人们同样有用
Really?
是吗？
I know much more than those who have never lived on a limited income.
我比那些从未尝过清贫滋味的人 要了解得更多
Just like the man or woman on the street, when I am short one week...
和普通人没有什么不同 假如我这一周比较拮据
I have to make economies the next.
下一周就需要更节省
Nothing like a slice of fiscal responsibility.
原来这不叫吝啬 或是守财啊
A man might call it fiscal responsibility, a woman might call it good housekeeping.
男人或许觉得这是守财 女人会认为这是勤俭持家
I’m not sure...
我不能说...
a home economics lesson is quite what...
如何处理家庭财务这件事...
the Dartford constituents need.
是成为达特佛德候选人的条件
They see industry being nationalized...
现在工业被国有化...
the unions on the up, the pound on the slide...
上有联盟 还有英镑问题
whoever can sort that lot out, he’s my man.
谁能解决这些事 才是我需要的男人
Or woman?
或者说女人？
Ladies shall we?
女士们，这边请？
Miss Roberts, do join the ladies.
罗伯茨小姐，请跟着其他女士
Well. That’s told us!
真是给我们上了一课啊
So, Margaret, how would you have dealt with this if you’d been Prime Minister?
玛格丽特，如果你还是首相 会如何处理这件事？
Where?
什么事？
The bombings, mummy. Today?
妈妈，今天的爆炸案
We were just talking about them?
我们刚才在说的
No, uhm, yes - we have always lived alongside evil.
噢是的 我们身边总有邪恶
But it has never been so patient,
但他们从未如此耐心
so avid for carnage, so eager to carry innocents with it into oblivion.
如此狂热地热衷杀戮 如此渴望伤及无辜
xxxSo, would you -
所以你会不会...
Western civilization must root out this evil, wherever it hides,
西方文明必须铲除这种邪恶 不管它藏身何处
or she risks defeat at the hands of global terror in a nuclear age.
不然就会有像核武器时代一样 被全球恐怖分子打败的危险
Unimaginable!
不可想象！
The Prime Minister gave a very good statement I thought.
首相发表了一份不错的演讲
Yes. Clever man. Quite a smoothie.
是的，聪明人，很圆滑
xxxYou don’t mind if I sit down...
你不介意的话我想坐下...
I heard you speak at conference in Brighton in 1984
1984年我听了您在布莱顿会议的演讲
just after the IRA bombed the Grand Hotel.
就在爱尔兰共和军 炸弹袭击了饭店之后
You were remarkable.
您的演讲非常出色
I hope you appreciate what an inspiration you have been for women like myself.
希望您能知道 您对女人，像我，有多大的鼓励
It used to be about trying to do something.
过去人们总是努力要做成某件事
Now its about trying to be someone.
现在是要努力成为某个人
Well anyway, I...thank you.
不论如何...谢谢您
Good night, Lady Th... - Good night to you.
- 晚安，撒切尔夫人 - 晚安
OK...hold on to me...
好的，扶住我...
Can you do the clasp, I can’t quite -
帮我解开一下，我不能...
Thank you.
谢谢
You’ve got an eyelash.
你掉了一根睫毛
Make a wish.
许个愿吧
I spoke to Doctor Michael today-
我今天和迈克尔医生聊了聊
He is very good and very expensive-
他是很好的医生，收费也高...
...I know you’re not due to see him for another month
我知道你还有一个月才需要去找他
but I’ve spoken to him and he can fit you in tomorrow.
不过我跟他打了招呼 他可以明天就看看你
Just for a check up.
只是做个检查
Ma please-
妈，拜托...
What does Mark think about it?
马克怎么说？
Mark?
马克？
Yes. Tell him to come up. I want to talk to him about it.
是啊，叫他上来 我得跟他商量一下
Mark’s with Sarah and the children.
马克和莎拉还有孩子们在一起
Well tell him to come up and see me after he’s...
那就让他...
kissed them good night, would you Carol darling?
和他们说过晚安以后再来找我 行不行，卡萝尔？
He’s not here Mummy.
妈妈，他不在这儿
Mark lives in South Africa...
马克现在住在南非...
you are not Prime Minister anymore...
你现在也不是首相了...
and Dad is... Dad is dead-
爸爸... 爸爸已经去世了
You look exhausted, dear.
你看上去累坏了
You really must try to get some sleep.
你真的应该多睡一些
Taxis'll be few and far between at this hour...
这个时候出租车也很少了...
Righty-ho. Night night Ma. Sleep well.
好吧 晚安妈妈，好好睡
Good night, dear.
晚安，亲爱的
Twenty-four-year-old Miss Margaret Roberts lost her bid to win a seat in Parliament today,
24岁的玛格丽特・罗伯茨小姐 失去了议会中的席位
but she has put new life into the Dartford Conservative Association.
但是她在达特佛德保守党联盟中 开展了新的事业
Winning candidate Mr Dodds had better watch out,
获胜候选人多兹先生可不能掉以轻心
this bright young woman is on his tail.
这位优秀的年轻女士正在迎头赶上
Eat!
吃吧！
Disaster.
糟透了
Hang on...Hang on...
等等...等等
You shaved thousands off their majority. You did splendidly.
你赢了他们大多数人 棒极了
Not splendidly enough.
还不够
Ah I see. Self pity.
我知道了，自我打击啊
No one is saying you don’t need a safe seat.
没人说你不需要这个位置
You deserve a safe seat.
你理应得到
But it does not come unless you learn to play the game a little.
但假如你不学着玩这场游戏 就很难赢
What game?
什么游戏？
You are a grocer’s daughter-
你是杂货商的女儿...
And proud of being. - in their eyes.
- 我很自豪 - 在他们看来
A single grocer’s daughter.
一个单身杂货商的女儿
But if you were to become the wife of a moderately successful businessman-
但假如你成为了一个 挺成功的商人的妻子...
You’d get to parliament,
你会进入议会
and I’d get to be the happiest man in...
我会成为最幸福的男人...
in wherever they select you.
不论他们将你选举去何处
Margaret, will you marry me?
玛格丽特，你愿意嫁给我吗？
Well?
嗯？
Yes. Yes!
是的，当然！
What?
怎么了？
I love you so much but...
我很爱你，但是...
I will never be one of those women Denis-
丹尼斯，我和其他女人不一样
who stays silent and pretty on the arm of her husband.
她们沉默，美丽 挽着丈夫的手
Or remote and alone in the kitchen doing the washing up for that matter.
或者远远地，呆在厨房里 做着清洁工作
We’ll get a help for that. - No...
- 我们可以请帮佣 - 不...
one’s life must matter, Denis.
一个人的生命必须是有意义的，丹尼斯
Beyond the cooking and the cleaning and the children,
要比做饭打扫带孩子更有意义
one’s life must mean more than that-
一个人的生命必须比这更丰富
I cannot die washing up a tea cup.
我不能洗茶杯直到终老
I mean it Denis,
我是说真的，丹尼斯
say you understand.
说，你理解我
That’s why I want to marry you, my dear.
我正是因为这个，才想要娶你的，亲爱的
Now eat.
现在可以吃了吧
There they are, my little twins.
你们在这呢 我的双胞胎宝贝们
Cornwall, wasn’t it? Bloody hell...
是康沃尔吧？ 天哪...
Look at ‘em, little imps.
看看他们，小恶魔
You never really got golf, did you?
你从来从没学会打高尔夫吧？
You look happy.
你看上去很开心
Yes, I do, don’t I? You’re drinking too much.
是啊，不是吗？ 你喝太多了
Whatcha doing?
你这是在干嘛？
Not like you. Looking back.
不像你啊，回忆过去
Don’t want to dig around too deep, M. Don’t know what you might find.
不会想挖掘得太深 因为你不知道你会发现什么
You can rewind it, but you can’t change it.
你可以倒带 但不能改变过去
They grow up so fast.
他们长大得太快了
Mr Eric Deakins,
埃里克・狄金斯先生
Labour... 13,437...
工党...13,437票
Mr xxxx lib... 12,260
埃文・斯宾塞先生，自由党 12,260票
Mrs Marg.. Thatcher
玛格丽特・撒切尔夫人
con... 29,697
保守党... 29,697票
xxx
我宣布1959年的选举获胜的是...
Mrs Marg.. Thatcher.
玛格丽特・撒切尔
xxx... Please.
记得照相... 拜托妈妈！
xxx
妈咪，不要走！
Mrs Thatcher!
撒切尔女士！
Mrs Thatcher! Airey Neave. Welcome to the madhouse. Follow me.
撒切尔女士！我是埃尔利・尼夫 欢迎来到这疯人院，跟我来
Order
肃静！
The Right Honourable Lady the Secretary of State for Education.
有请尊敬的教育大臣女士
The right honourable gentleman knows that we have no choice but to shut down the schools!
尊敬的各位先生，你们知道 我们别无选择，只能关闭学校
Because...
因为...
his union paymasters have called a strike deliberately to cripple our economy.
工会故意进行了罢工 来削弱我们的经济
Teachers cannot teach when there is no heating, no lighting in their classrooms.
教室里没有供暖，没有灯光 教师是没法进行教学的
And I ask the honourable gentleman, whose fault is that?
请问在座各位 这是谁的错？
Me thinks the Right Honourable lady doth screech to much.
我认为这位女士大呼小叫得太多了
If she wants us to take her seriously she must learn to calm down!
如果她想让我们严肃对待 自己就得先学着淡定！
If the right honorable gentleman could perhaps attend more closely to...
如果这位先生您可以 多注意一下...
What I am saying, rather than HOW I am saying it,
我说话的内容 而不是我说话的方式
he may receive a valuable education in spite of himself!
他或许可以接受到更好的教育！
Why has this Conservative government failed?
为什么这一届保守党政府失利了？
Why has it forced so many in the public sector into
为什么政府让这么多的公共部门
taking strike action to save their own jobs?
只能以罢工 来保存自己的工作职位？
Minister...
大臣女士...
the breakdown of essential public services in transport, electricity...
必要的公共设施比如 交通，电力，卫生...
sanitation is not the fault of the trades unions...
它们出的问题并不在于工会...
but of this Conservative government
而是这一届保守党政府
in which you so shamefully serve!
也就是你司职的这一届 令人不齿的政府！
So these power cuts will continue unless we can reach a compromise.
停电还将继续 除非我们可以达成妥协
The miners are asking for a 35% increase in wages.
矿工们需要薪水涨35%
Obviously we can’t go anywhere near that.
显然我们不能答应这个要求
The unions are not our enemies and never have been.
工会不是我们的敌人 从来都不是
We want- and have always wanted the broadest consensus…
我们想要，并一直想要达成共识
I’m sure we are all in agreement that we must do nothing...
我肯定大家一定一致同意 我们绝对不能...
for the moment that will further inflame the current situation.
现在做任何煽风点火的事
Hear hear, Prime Minister.
是的，是的，首相大人
- the fact of the matter is, it’s absolutely crucial...
残酷的事实是...
that we are seen by the public to be acting as conciliators...
我们在公众看来是在和解
and not aggressors. - Yes.
- 而不是侵略者 - 是的
Yes, Education Secretary.
请说，教育大臣
Yes, Prime Minister.
是的，首相大人
With the Miners’ leader calling today for the army to mutiny...
今天听说矿工领导人 要发动军事暴乱...
in support of the strikes, this seems the wrong time for conciliation.
用来支持罢工事件 现在妥协似乎不大合适
Be patient. They’ll come back on in a minute.
耐心点，一会儿就会来电
Thank you, Margaret.
谢谢，玛格丽特
Your thoughts are duly noted.
你的想法我们会考虑
We on this island are strong.
我们是强大的岛国人民
We’re self-reliant. Napoleon called us a nation of shopkeepers.
我们自给自足 拿破仑说我们是个做小生意的国家
He meant it as an insult but to me it’s a compliment.
他说这话是羞辱 但我认为这是赞扬
That’s why he couldn’t beat us, and that’s why Hitler can’t beat us.
这就是为何他不能战胜我们 也是为何希特勒不能战胜我们
We Conservatives believe in giving people the freedom and opportunity to...
我们保守党坚信 让人们有自由去...
fulfil their own potential, especially the young.
发掘完善自己的潜能 尤其是年轻人
There’s no good in pretending we’re all equal...
假装人人平等是没有好处的
we’re not all the same, never have been, never will be.
每个人都不同，从来都不是 也永远不会一样
We should encourage our children to aspire to achieve more than we have...
我们应该鼓励孩子们 立志追求比父辈更多的东西
for our children today will be the leaders of tomorrow.
今天的孩子 就是明天的领袖
It’s 1974 and you’d think it was WWII.
已经1974年了 你会觉得这还是第二次世界大战
Blackouts, no petrol. It’s a mess.
停电，没有汽油 一片混乱
Heath should resign now and make way for someone who’s not afraid to tackle the unions.
希思首相应该辞职 让不害怕解决工会的人上任
I swear, it’s all gone completely out of my head.
我发誓，我完全忘记了
My driving instructor thinks I should pass but I feel as if I’ve hardly had any lessons.
我的驾车指导认为我可以通过 但我觉得我似乎没有上过任何课
Ridiculous isn’t it? Maybe third time lucky.
很没道理吧？ 或许只能寄希望于事不过三吧
Right.
是啊
The only thing you should remember is that everyone else is either reckless or inept.
你只要记住，其他人 不是无能，就是鲁莽
And often both.
通常两者都是
One must be brave if one is to take the wheel-
一个人如果要开始承担责任 就需要更勇敢
Right-o.
是啊
Move over... Move to your right a little bit...
开过去一些... 右边去一点
But if I move to the right aren’t I on the wrong side of the road?
如果我开到右边去了 不就逆行了吗？
Well he’s in the way! - To the right. Move to the right!
- 他在路中间！ - 右边，开到右边去！
So sorry! Terribly sorry!
抱歉！十分抱歉！
Hey, look at me, driving!
嘿，看我！我在开车！
Thanks Ma, that was terrific! I really feel I’ve got a handle on it now.
谢谢妈，太棒了！ 我觉得我可以很好地控制了
You should have seen us, Pa.
你应该看看我们的，爸
Have you been trying to make breakfast? For Goodness sake, Denis!
天哪，丹尼斯！ 你这是要自己做早饭？
I can boil a bloody egg.
煮个蛋总可以吧
Mummy took me for a test drive -
妈妈带我去试驾了
We went absolutely everywhere. All over the place -
我们到处开，去了很多地方
I’ve decided. I’m going to run.
我决定了，我要竞选
What for?
竞选什么？
I’m going to run for Leader of the Party.
我要竞选保守党党魁
Silly me! - Good luck!
- 我真笨！ - 祝好运啊！
All the time I thought I was having a driving lesson, it was all about my mother, just for a change!
每次我总觉得自己是要上驾驶课 其实都是和妈妈有关，哪怕只有一次！
What’s she on about?
她又是怎么了？
It’s her driving test this morning! - Oh, right. Of course.
- 今天早上她要考驾照！ - 噢，是啊，当然
Are you saying you want to be Prime Minister?
你是说你想要当首相？
What I’m saying is that someone must force the point,
我是说 总得有人面对问题
say the unsayable. None of these men have the guts.
说出难以启齿的话 这些男人都没有胆子
The Prime Minister has been very loyal to you, MT.
首相大人一直是站在你这边的，玛格丽特
But he’s weak, and he’s weakened the party.
但他也很软弱 他让整个党都变得软弱了
One must know when to go. You’re shaking.
一个人必须知道何时该出手 你在发抖
Let... xxx - I can do it!
- 我来... - 我能行！
Goodness me!
上帝保佑我啊！
What is the matter with everyone this morning?
今天一大早大家这都是怎么了？
I’ve told you what the matter is.
我已经告诉你怎么回事了
The business is a bit rocky at the moment and the Doctor thinks I need a rest.
生意有些岌岌可危 医生告诉我需要休息
And do you need a rest?
你需要休息吗？
We both know...
我们都知道...
that it’s highly unlikely that I would ever be elected leader,
把我选为领导人 是非常不可能的
But I will run. I will run.
但是我会去竞选
Just to nip at their heels and make...
只是发出我的讯号
them reaffirm the principles on which the Conservative Party must stand.
让他们重申 保守党应该坚持的原则
There’s so much to do.
有好多事要做呢
You’re insufferable, Margaret, do you know that?
你真是让人难以忍受，玛格丽特 你知道吗？
Denis, you married someone who is committed to public service, you knew that.
丹尼斯，你娶了一个终生以 服务大众为己业的人，你知道的
And it is my duty... - Don’t call it duty.
- 这是我的责任... - 不要称这个为责任
It’s ambition which has got you this far. Ambition.
是政治抱负让你走到今天 政治野心
And the rest of us, me, the children, we can all go to hell!
我们其他人，我，孩子们 我们都好去死了！
Don’t worry about me, I’ll be fine!
别担心我 我没事！
Where did you go?
你那时候去哪了？
South Africa. - Yes.Yes.
- 南非 - 是啊，对
How many days passed before you realized I was gone?
你发觉我走了的时候 已经过了多少天了？
Probably had to ask the cleaning woman where I was.
大概还得问问清洁工 我上哪里去了
When did I lose track of everyone?
我是什么时候变得跟大家如此脱节的？
Too busy climbing the greasy pole MT.
太忙于向上爬了，玛格丽特
Mrs Thatcher I understand you recently visited the United States of America.
撒切尔女士，我知道你最近 访问了美国
What was it you took away from that visit which may be of value here in Great Britain?
你在这次访问中有没有获取经验 来造福大英？
Oh that’s rather easy to answer, actually.
噢这个其实很容易回答
They are unafraid of success.
他们不惧怕成功
We in Great Britain and in Europe are formed mainly by our history.
我们英国，还有欧洲 主要建立在悠久的历史上
They on the other hand are formed by their philosophy.
而大洋彼岸的他们 建立在他们自己的哲学上
Not by what has been, but by what can be.
不是建立在过去 而是未来
Oh, we have a great deal that we can learn from them, yes. Oh yes!
噢，有太多我们可以学习的了 噢，是的！
For a start, that hat has got to go.
首先，帽子不能戴了
And the pearls.
还有珍珠项链
In fact I think all hats may have to go.
事实上我觉得都不该戴帽子
You look and sound like...
你看上去、听起来就像...
a privileged Conservative wife and we’ve already got her vote.
一个有特权的保守党妻子 我们已经得到了她的选票
You’ve got lovely hair...
你的头发很漂亮...
but we need to do something with it to make it more, Important.
但我们还是需要尽兴修饰 让它变得更...醒目
Yes. Give it more impact.
是的，变得更醒目
But the main thing is your voice. Its too high. It has no authority.
但最关键的还是声音 音调太高，没有权威性
Me thinks the Lady doth screech too much
我确实认为女人喜欢大呼小叫
People don’t want to be harangued by a woman or hectored.
人们不喜欢跟女人高谈阔论 或是被领导
Persuaded yes. That ‘oh yes’...
或是被劝说 那个“噢，是的”
at the end of the interview,
这个访谈最后的那句
that’s authoritative, that’s the voice of a leader.
那句就有权威性 那才是领袖的声音
It’s all very well to talk about changing my voice, Mr Reece,
让我改变说话声没问题，瑞斯先生
but for some of my colleagues to imagine me as their leader...
但如果让我的一些同事们 想象让我来当领导人...
would be like imagining,
就好像是在说
I don’t know, being led into battle by their chambermaid.
我不知道 像是被女侍者引起了战争
It’s my background, and my sex.
我的个人背景，我的性别
No matter how I’ve tried, and I have tried...
不管我如何努力 而我确实也努力了...
to fit in, xxx I will never be truly one of them.
努力融入 我永远不能真正成为他们一员
If I may say so - I think that’s your trump card.
如果让我说... 我觉得这才是你的王牌
You’re flying in the face of everything the Tories have been thus far.
你目前为止已经出现在 保守党所有事件里了
It’s really very exciting.
这很让人兴奋
One simply has to maximise your appeal...
现在只需要 最大化你的申请...
bring out all your qualities...
展现出你所有的个人素养...
and make you look, and sound, like the leader that you could be.
让你看上去 听上去 都更像一个领导人
You’ve got it in you to go the whole distance.
你最终会获得你想要的
Absolutely.
绝对
Prime Minister?!
首相？
Oh no. Oh no no no. In Britain?
噢，不，不不不 英国的首相？
There will be no female Prime Minister here, not in my lifetime.
不会有女首相的 至少在我活着的时候
No.
不
And I told Airey, I don’t expect to win the leadership, but I...
我也告诉艾利了 我不曾想过要赢得领导权...
am going to run. Just to shake up the party.
我只是要竞选 让党内的人醒一醒
Respectfully, Margaret,
玛格丽特，我很尊重你
I disagree. If you want to change this party,
但是我不同意 如果你想要改变这个政党
lead it. If you want to change the country, lead it.
就去亲自领导它 如果你想要改变这个国家，就去亲自领导它
What we’re talking about here today is surface. What’s crucial...
我们今天讨论的还都是表面问题
is that you hold your course, and stay true to who you are.
重要的是，你要坚定立场 做出自己的风格
Never be anything other than yourself.
永远不要成为其他人
Leave us to do the rest.
让我们来做其他事
Gentlemen, I am in your hands.
先生们，那么我就交给你们了
I may be persuaded to surrender the hat.
或许我可以不戴帽子了
But the pearls were a gift from my husband on the birth of our twins...
但这珍珠项链是我丈夫 在我双胞胎孩子们的生日时候送给我的
and they are absolutely non-negotiable.
这件事没法妥协
Good, I think we can loose the handbag, Mrs Thatcher.
很好，可以放下手袋了，撒切尔女士
Hands down the sides...
手放在两边...
And...bring it down.
从上...到下
Because this isn’t really about the voice, it’s about belief...
这其实不是关乎声音 是关乎信念...
A nice deep breath.
来个深呼吸
xxx hands
伸手
If you’re calling Mr Thatcher, how would you do that?
你要叫撒切尔先生的话 会怎么叫？
Denis.
丹尼斯
Yes, I want more authority, I want conviction, I want...
是的，我需要更多的权威性 更多的信服力...
That’s right, one more time, deep breath -
对了，再来一次 深呼吸...
Denis.
丹尼斯！
Yes MT!
是的，玛格丽特！
You are the backbone of our nation!
你们是我们国家的脊梁骨！
Small firms like Loveday’s Ice Cream.
像Loveday冰淇淋这样的小公司
How are you? So nice to meet you ladies.
你们好 真高兴见到你们
I’ll just have a small one, because I’m watching my figure.
我就吃小小一个 我还得注意身材
That’s for you young man!
年轻人，这个给你的！
I passionately believe it’s the growth of small businesses into larger ones...
我坚信小生意发展成大生意的过程...
that is critical for Britain’s future.
对英国的未来很重要
It has to be something icy on a stick for Denis.
丹尼斯的贴纸上 得有冰淇淋图案了
That’s the only way...
这也是唯一的方法...
we will produce jobs, real jobs, jobs that sustain.
来提供真正的工作 有持续力的工作
The Trade Union Movement was founded to protect workers.
工会运动的开始 是为了保护工人
Now it persecutes them. It stops them from working.
现在变成了困扰 他们没办法工作了
It is killing jobs and it is bringing this country to its knees.
工会减少了工作机会 让整个国家陷入困境
I say enough.
我说得够多了
It’s time to get up. It’s time to go to work.
是时候站起来了 是时候去工作了
It’s time to put the Great back into Great Britain!
是时候让大不列颠重上巅峰了！
Give ‘em hell!
给他们点颜色看看！
You look magnificent. Next stop Prime Minister.
你看上去棒极了 下一站，首相
Let go.
走吧
The leader of the Conservative Party, Margaret Thatcher!
保守党党魁 玛格丽特・撒切尔
Good night Margaret. My money’s on the filly to win!
晚安玛格丽特 我的钱可全押了你赢！
Oh, thanks Airey. Goodnight.
噢，谢谢你艾利 晚安
No. No, no! Airey!
不，不，不！ 艾利！
The Irish National Liberation Army has claimed responsibility for the...
爱尔兰共和军宣称..
death of Airey Neave, Margaret Thatcher’s spokesman on Northern Ireland.
对玛格丽特・撒切尔的北爱尔兰发言人 艾利・尼夫的死亡负责
If you want to change the party, lead it.
如果你想要改变这个政党 就去亲自领导它
If you want to change the country, lead it.
如果你想要改变这个国家
You’ve got it in you to go the whole distance!
你会取得最终胜利 来领导这个国家
Now, as the test draws near, I ask your help.
大选临近的时候 我需要你们帮助我
That together we can shake off the shackles of socialism
我们可以一起摆脱 社会主义的枷锁
and restore to greatness this country that we love.
重拾我们热爱的这个国家的伟大
And the only way is for the Conservative Party to win!
唯一的方法 就是让保守党当选！
xxx
保守党支持率上升
It’s Friday the 4th of May, an historic day for Britain,
今天是五月四号星期五 英国历史上应被记住的一天
a Conservative government led by Mrs. Thatcher is set to lead -
由撒切尔夫人领导的保守党当选为...
Mrs Ghandi in India, but never in the West has there been a woman Prime Minister.
印度有甘地夫人 但西方还从未有过女性首相
The place that she has secured in British history, as...
她在英国历史上写下了重重一笔...
the first woman ever to be invited to form a government.
作为第一个可以自己组建政府的女性
The bonus of one of the most famous addresses in the world,
附赠礼物是世界上最著名的地址之一
Number 10 Downing Street.
唐宁街10号
This is it, steady the buffs old girl.
我们到了 要稳住哦，大姑娘
Good afternoon, Prime Minister.
下午好，首相大人
I should just like to say...
我只想说...
that I take very seriously the trust...
我会更严肃对待...
the British people placed in me today...
英国人民今天给我的信任
and I will work hard every day to live up to that responsibility.
我会夜以继日地努力工作 来履行自己的职责
And now, I should like to share with you a prayer...
现在，我想和你们分享这个祝祷词...
of St Francis of Assisi:
来自方济 （意大利会士和主保圣人，生于1182年）
''Where there is discord may we bring harmony...
“凡是有不和的地方 我们要为和谐而努力”
Where there is error may we bring truth...
“凡是有谬误的地方 我们要为真理而努力”
Where there is doubt may we bring faith...
“凡是有疑虑的地方 我们要为信任而努力”
Where there is despair may we bring hope''
“凡是有绝望的地方 我们要为希望而努力”
Shoulders back, tummies in!
挺肩，收腹！
Oh. Thank you, Michael.
噢谢谢你，迈克尔
Two, one.
三，二，一...
I’m perfectly healthy. There’s no need for any of this.
我很健康 没必要做这些
Just let them look under the bonnet, MT.
就让他们给你检查检查吧
Check everything is hunky dory.
正好看看一切都很好
Really it’s becoming quite tiresome.
这真的开始变得很烦人啊
What is? - You.
- 什么很烦人？ - 你
I was on my own for twenty four years...
认识你之前 我独自一人生活了24年...
before I met you and I can manage perfectly well without you now.
我当时可以很好 现在没有了你当然也行
So will you please go away and stop bothering me.
所以快走开 不要再烦我了
Just look straight at me, straight ahead, that’s it.
直视我 向前直视，对
Are you noticing night sweats? - No.
- 有发现夜间盗汗吗？ - 没有
Hallucinations?
有过幻觉？
No.
没有
Sleep?
睡眠呢？
Yes, I sleep. Four, five hours a night.
睡眠还行 每晚有四五个小时
So you wake early?
所以你会很早就醒来？
And I stay up late. I always have.
我会熬夜，经常熬夜
We just want to keep abreast of it thats all.
我们只是想要了解你的情况
Yes. Of course.
噢当然
Grief is a very natural state.
悲伤是很正常的情绪
My husband has been gone for years. Cancer.
我的丈夫已经去世多年了 因为癌症
Carol says you’ve decided to let his things go. Probably a good thing.
卡萝尔说你已经决定把他的遗物送走 大概会是件好事吧
Yes. It was my idea. To Oxfam.
是的，是我的主意 送去乐施会
Perfectly good stuff. People can use these things.
都是很好的东西 人们可以用得上
Still it must be a bit disorientating. You are bound to be feeling.
可是还是会有些茫然吧 你一定会这么觉得
What?
什么？
What am I ‘bound to be feeling’?
一定会觉得怎么样？
People don’t ‘think’ any more.
人们已经不“思考”了
They ‘feel’. ‘How are you feeling?’
只是“感觉” “你感觉如何？”
‘Oh I don’t feel comfortable with that’
“噢，那个让我觉得不太舒服”
‘Oh, I’m so sorry but we, the group were feeling...’
“噢，很抱歉，但是我们， 我们团队，感到...”
D’you know, one of the great problems of our age...
你知道吗 这个时代最大的问题...
is that we are governed by people who care...
我们是被这样的人们领导着...
more about feelings than thoughts and ideas.
他们注重感觉 多于思考和想法
Now thoughts and ideas. That interests me.
思考和想法才能让我感兴趣
Ask me what I am thinking-
问问我在“想”什么...
What are you thinking, Margaret?
那么你在想什么呢，玛格丽特？
Watch your thoughts, for they become words.
注意你所想的 因为它们会变成嘴里的话
Watch your words, for they become actions.
注意你所说的 因为它们会变成实际的行动
Watch your actions, for they become habits.
注意你的行为 因为它们会形成习惯
Watch your habits, for they become your character.
注意你的习惯 因为它们会形成你的人格
And watch your character, for it becomes your destiny.
注意你的人格 因为它们会影响你的命运
What we think, we become.
我们想的是什么 就会成为什么样的人
My father always said that.
我的父亲一直这样说
And I think I am fine.
我“认为”，我很好
But I do so appreciate your kind concern.
但我还是很谢谢你的关心
Oh, do please answer that.
噢，去接电话吧
It might be someone who needs you.
或许是有真正需要你的人
I’ll give Carol a quick ring, let her...
我会给卡萝尔打个电话...
know we’re back, then I’ll put your electric blanket on.
让她知道我们回来了 然后我会给你铺上电热毯
Steady, steady, steady!
停，停，停！
Damn. Fore!
该死 跑远了
What about that medicine man, eh?
那个医生怎样啊？
Ah. Cold supper.
啊，晚餐冷了
Standards are slipping Margaret.
标准正在慢慢变化 玛格丽特
Well you really gave it to that quack didn’t you, darling?
你真的告诉了那个庸医了吧？
Just like the old days! Hallucinations my eye!
跟以前一样！ 还是会幻觉看见我！
How dare he?
他哪来的胆问？
But then you give us all the run around, don’t you?
但是你没把我们的事告诉他，是吧？
I know you can hear me, sweetheart, so there’s no use pretending you can’t.
我知道你能听见我说话，亲爱的 装作听不见是没用的
Enough. Denis, enough!
够了，丹尼斯，够了！
Dismissed!
退下咯
She does it in the end. Kills him-
她最后还是做了 杀了他
I don’t know why you’re being so scratchy.
我不知道你为什么变得这么冷漠
It’s not as if you’ve got anyone else to talk to.
其实你也没有别的人可以说话
When the Himalayan peasant meets the he-bear in his pride -
“当喜马拉雅农夫看见这头公的熊...
You know, it’s a marvel to me that you can still quote huge chunks of Kipling...
你知道吗，对我来说你仍旧能引用 这么多吉卜林的诗是有多神奇
but try remembering the name of that woman who’s...
但试着回想一下那个女人叫什么...
just made you that godawful cold collation.
是她让你整理这些东西
No?
不记得？
Come on. You can do it.
你能想起来的
Month of the year.
你一年中的一个月份
One syllable. Rhymes with moon.
一个音节 和“月亮（moon）”押韵
June. - June! Bingo.
- 琼 - 是琼！答对了
Knew you’d get there in the end.
就知道你会想起来的
“When the Himalayan peasant meets the he-bear in his pride...
“当喜马拉雅农夫遇到这头公熊...”
He shouts to scare the monster, who will often turn aside...
“他大喊，震慑这头猛兽 通常已会退却...”
but the she-bear thus accosted rends the peasant tooth and nail.
“但是母熊因而撕下了 农夫的牙齿和指甲”
For the female of the species is more deadly than the male...”
“女性物种 总是比男性物种更致命...”
If I can’t hear you then I can’t see you.
如果我听不见你说话 那我也就看不见你了
And if I can’t see you then you are not here.
如果我看不见你了 你就不存在了
And if you are not here, I am not going mad.
如果你不存在 我就没有发疯了
I will not go mad.
我不会发疯的
I will not...
我不会... 我不会发疯
Baroness Thatcher made an apparently routine visit to her doctor today.
撒切尔夫人今天例行 又去见了她的医生
Although rarely seen in public,
虽然已经很少出现在公众场合
the longest serving Prime Minister of the twentieth century,
这位20世纪任期最长的首相
remains a controversial figure.
仍旧是个有争议的人物
Almost lovingly dubbed by the Soviets The Iron Lady,
被苏维埃政府戏称为“铁娘子”
she’s also credited, with her friend Ronald Reagan,
她和她的好友，罗纳德・里根 一同被认为是...
with a decisive role in the ending of the Cold War.
结束冷战的决定性人物
Her supporters claim she transformed the British...
她的支持者认为她 改变了英国的经济...
economy and reversed the country’s post-war decline.
阻止了英国的战后萧条
Her detractors blame her savage public spending...
而反对她的人 职责她野蛮的公共开支...
cuts and sweeping privatization of -
削减和治理私有化....
I don’t recognize myself.
我都认不出自己了
Am I out of the doghouse yet?
我还没搬离这个狗屋吗？
They’re unveiling that portrait...
他们要把我的画像揭幕...
of me at Number 10 next month.
下个月在首相府
The invitation’s on the mantelpiece.
邀请函在壁炉台上
So...
所以...
there’ll be Churchill,
那里现在有丘吉尔的画像
Lloyd George and me.
大卫・劳合・乔治，还有我 （大卫・劳合・乔治，英国自由党首领，英国首相，任期1916至1922）
Just the three of us.
只有我们三个人
I said I didn’t want any big fuss but they insisted.
我说过不想小题大做 不过他们坚持要
Lovely little article in The Telegraph.
《每日电讯报》这文章真不错
The Woman Who Changed the Face of History.
“改变了历史容颜的女人”
Less than two years ago,
还不到两年前...
the Prime Minister quoted St. Francis...
首相引用了方济的话...
and talked about bringing faith,
还说要努力给这个国家
hope and harmony to this country.
带来信任、希望、和谐
Denis?
丹尼斯？
Can the Right Honourable Lady deny,
尊敬的首相夫人不能否认的是
that having brought about the highest level...
自从1934年以来...
of unemployment since 1934-
最高的失业率
The biggest fall in total output...
1931年以来...
in steel and coal production in one year since 1931.
最低的钢铁和煤矿的出口...
And the biggest collapse in industrial production since 1921.
自从1921年以来 最严重的工业衰退
Order, Order.
肃静，肃静
Can she also accept that her free market economics...
她还得承认 她的自由市场经济...
designed to create a growing middle class...
本想要扶持中产阶级...
ensures that the rich get richer and the poor are irrelevant!
只让有钱人变得更有钱 而与穷人无关！
Maggie Maggie Maggie! Out Out Out!
玛姬！玛姬！出来！出来！
You’re supposed to be a mother!
你本应该是个母亲！
You’re not a mother, you’re a monster!
你不是母亲 你是野兽！
May we have a word, Prime Minister?
能和你说几句吗，首相？
Yes, but in order to arrive at the palace on time,
可以，但为了准时到达王宫
Geoffrey and I are will be walking out of that door in 15 minutes.
杰弗里和我15分钟之后出发
As you can see. - I know you’re running late Margaret...
- 你也看得出来 - 我知道你快要迟了，玛格丽特...
but we have to address this situation in light...
但是现在这个情况...
of tomorrow’s blistering press coverage. Blistering!
必须在明天的发布会上 发表严厉声明。严厉的！
The knives are out.
我们已是众矢之的
Your draft budget’s been leaked, Geoffrey, they are baying for our blood!
你的预算草案已经泄露了 杰弗里，人们已厉声地以死相逼
Michael we can’t possibly buckle at the first sign of difficulty.
迈克尔...我们不可能一出现问题 就如此紧张
No one is saying we have to buckle. - But is this really the time to...
- 没人说我们要紧张 - 但现在真的必须...
make these spending cuts in the middle of one of the deepest...
削减财政支出...
recessions this country has ever experienced?
在这个国家最萧条的时候？
We need a plan of action, Margaret. - Absolutely. A strategy.
- 我们需要计划一下接下来的政策，玛格丽特 - 当然，计划政策
We must be armed.
我们必须武装好自己
There’s a perception, Margaret...
我有这种感觉，玛格丽特...
rightly or wrongly, that we are now completely out of touch with the country.
不管是对是错 感觉我们已经跟这个国家完全脱节了
Really. How much is a pack of Lurpak?
是吗？ 一包Lurpak（黄油品牌）多少钱？
Lurpak? - Butter, Francis.
- Lurpak? - 是个黄油牌子，弗朗西斯
Forty two pence.
四十二便士
Anchor butter is forty pence.
Anchor黄油是40便士
Flora margarine, still the cheapest, is thirty eight pence.
Flora植物黄油，仍旧最便宜 38便士
I can assure you I am not out of touch.
我敢向你保证 我没有脱节
“Grocer’s Daughter”
“杂货店老板的女儿”
What - did you say?
抱歉... 你刚才说什么？
Nothing. Prime Minister, Nothing.
没什么，首相大人
No, no, please. Don’t try to hide you opinions.
不，请不要隐藏自己的想法
Goodness me, I’d much rather you were open and...
天哪，我多么希望你们能开诚布公...
straight forward about them
有什么就直说
instead of continuously and damagingly leaking them to the press.
而不是持续地恶意地 透露给媒体
Well? - Well,
- 所以呢？ - 所以...
people can’t pay their mortgages.
人们无法负担他们的抵押物
The manufacturing industry is practically on its knees.
制造工业几乎已经瘫痪
Honest, hard-working, decent people are losing their homes.
诚信、吃苦耐劳的人们 正在失去家园
It’s terribly shameful.
真是莫大的羞耻
The point is, Prime Minister, that we must moderate the pace -
关键问题是，首相大人 我们必须缓下步伐...
- if we’re even to have a hope of winning the next election-
假如我们甚至都没有希望 赢下下一次的大选...
Quite right. Ah. Worried about our careers, are we?
是啊是啊 在担心我们的职业前途了，是吧？
Gentlemen, if we don’t cut spending we will be bankrupt.
先生们，如果我们不削减开支 我们就会破产
Yes, the medicine is harsh...
的确，良药都是苦口...
but the patient requires it in order to live.
但病人们只有服药才能继续活下去
Shall we withhold the medicine? No! We are not wrong.
我们能把这药停了吗？ 不！我们没有错
We did not seek election and win in order to manage...
我们没有利用选举的胜利...
the decline of a great nation.
来让这个伟大的国家走向衰退
The people of this country chose us...
这个国家的人民选择了我们...
because they believe we can restore the health of
因为他们相信我们可以...
the British economy and we will do just that!
重振英国的经济 我们会做到的！
Barring a failure of nerve.
不许因为胆怯而失败
Anything else? - Prime Minister.
- 还有别的事吗？ - 首相大人
You saved the day once again, Crawfie,
你再一次救了我，克洛菲
you’re an angel.
你真好
You can’t close down a discussion because it’s not what you wish to hear.
你不能因为这些话你不想听 就强行让这谈话结束
I don’t expect everyone just to sit there and agree with me.
我并不希望每个人只是 坐在那里，对我点头哈腰
But what kind of leader am I if I don’t try to get my own way-
假如我不努力坚持自己的路 我算是哪门子的领导人呢
to do what I know to be right. - Yes.
- 我必须做自己认为对的事 - 是的
But Margaret,
但是玛格丽特
one must be careful of testing one’s colleagues’ loyalty too far.
一个人在试探自己同僚们的忠诚度的时候 要小心不要过火
We are now one split nation,
国家正残破不堪
with a huge gulf dividing the employed from the unemployed.
有工作的人和失业的人之间 有着巨大的隔阂
The Thatcher plan is to break the Trade Union movement.
撒切尔夫人的想法 是要结束工会运动
There must be closures of uneconomic coal mines,
不经济的煤矿必须关闭
we seek only an efficient industry.
我们只需要高效率的工业
The miners are being starved back to work, the need is desperate!
煤矿工人走投无路必须回去工作 有着极其绝望的需求量
There are those who would say hold back,
会有人说不要做到这地步
there are those who would make us retreat -
会有人劝我们退缩
But we shall never give in to them.
但我们永远不会向他们妥协
We shall never waver, not for a second,
我们永远不会动摇 哪怕只是一秒
in our determination to see this country prosper once again.
我们坚定不移地 一定要让这个国家重新繁荣昌盛
A car bomb has exploded outside Harrods department store, killing...
哈洛兹百货商店门口 发生一起汽车炸弹袭击事件
six people and injuring 71.
6人死亡，71人受伤
Eleven soldiers died today when two bombs were detonated during...
今天两个炸弹引爆 致使11名士兵死亡...
military parades in Hyde Park and Regent’s Park.
在今天海德公园和摄政公园 的阅兵仪式上
Seven horses also died in the blasts.
7匹战马也在爆炸中死亡
The IRA have claimed responsibility.
爱尔兰共和军宣称对事件负责
And now, it must be business as usual.
现在，仍旧一切照常
Come on love, get to bed.
亲爱的，来睡觉吧
I don’t know why you do this to yourself every year,
我不明白你为何每年 都要这样
it’s a speech at conference, not the Magna Carta!
只是在大会发言又不是修改宪章
Time to call it a day, darling. It’s ten to three, for God’s sake.
该睡觉了，亲爱的 天哪，都3点差10分了
I know, I’m coming DT. Nearly there -
我知道，就来了 快要好了
Denis!
丹尼斯！
Denis-
丹尼斯...
there you are. Are you alright?
你在呢！ 没事吧？
My shoes!
我的鞋！
That’s when I thought I’d lost you.
那一刻 我觉得我差点要失去你了
Mark?
马克？
Hello darling.
你好，亲爱的
No, I’m fine.
不，我很好
I’m very well, How is...
我很好，你那边...
Sarah?
莎拉好吗？
And the children..?
孩子们呢？
Oh...
噢...
You can’t.
噢你来不了了
That’s a pity.
真遗憾
I was hoping to see you.
我还很想见你呢
Yes...
是...
Oh... No That’s fine. Really darling.
噢，没关系 真的
That’s fine.
没关系
Of course... another time.
当然... 改天吧
Yes... Darling.
是...亲爱的
Yes... Can’t wait... Lovely.
是的...等不及了 真好
Yes...
是的...
xxx Mark?
马克？
That was Mark. Not able to come.
是马克打来的 他不能来了
Boy’s always going AWOL.
男孩子们总是擅自离开
Well it costs him a great deal to fly everyone up here.
他如果要全家都飞过来 也要花一笔钱
There you go, making excuses for him. Now look where it’s got you.
你看你，给他找借口 看看他把你给折腾的
Did you know Yul Brynner was a gypsy from Vladivostok?
你知不知道尤尔・伯连纳（俄国裔美国戏剧演员） 是来自海参崴的吉普赛人？
Yes. He moved to Paris when he was fourteen.
是的，他14岁的时候移居巴黎
He played the King of Siam...
他演出了暹罗王...
4,625 times on the London and Broadway stages.
一共在百老汇和伦敦的舞台上 总计4625次
What are you doing?
你在干嘛？
One likes to make an effort. A snifter?
总有人要做点事啊 喝酒吗？
You’re dead, Denis.
你已经死了，丹尼斯
Ah. Well, if I’m dead... who are you talking to? Shall we dance?
啊，那么，如果我死了... 你在跟谁说话呢？跳支舞吧？
The Falkland islands, the British Colony in the South Atlantic, has fallen.
英国南大西洋殖民地 福克兰群岛，沦陷了
Argentina claims its marines went ashore as a spearhead this morning...
阿根廷宣称其海军部队已经 于今早登陆
to capture key targets, including the capital, Port Stanley.
有几个主要目标 包括首府斯坦利港
Gentlemen, the Argentinian Junta...
先生们 阿根廷军政府...
which is a fascist gang...
一群法西斯黑帮分子...
has invaded our sovereign territory. This cannot be tolerated.
侵犯了我们的主权领土 这种行为我们不能纵容
May I make plain my negotiating position.
我需要表明我的谈判立场
I will not negotiate with criminals or thugs.
我不会和罪犯或是恶棍谈判
The Falkland islands belong to Britain, and I want them back.
福克兰群岛属于大英帝国 我要夺回它们
Gentlemen, I need you to tell me today if that is possible.
先生们，我需要你们今天就告诉我 这是否可行
Possible... just, Prime Minister.
只是...有可能性，首相
We can have a Task Force ready to sail in forty-eight hours.
我们可以在48小时内 成立行动组出发
Forty-eight hours? But...
- 48小时？ - 但是...
We have a very narrow weather window.
天气情况对我们很不利
We can’t fight in winter down there. Nobody can.
南半球正是严冬 我们无法作战 没人可以
If we are going, we have to go now.
如果我们要走 就要现在出发
Why were the islands left without any naval protection?
为什么那些岛屿会没有任何海军保护？
In the last round of Defence cuts we judged the risk of invasion to be small.
上一次的国防预算削减 我们判断有人侵略的可能性很低
Did we?
是吗？
And if you remember, Prime Minister,
如果你能想起来的话，是的
you agreed that we should reduce the naval presence in the area to an absolute minimum.
你同意我们应该把那个地区的 海军防卫削减到最少
Margaret, the cost of sending 28,000 men...
玛格丽特，我们派去28,000人 的总开支...
and a hundred ships twelve thousand miles, almost to Argentina, will be absolutely crippling.
还有一百艘战舰航行12,000英里 几乎是到了阿根廷 会让我们经济瘫痪
I don’t think we should be worrying about money at this point, Geoffrey.
我不认为这件事上我们还需要 担心钱的问题 杰弗里
We can’t afford to go to war.
我们打不起仗的
We have to go now.
我们必须现在就出发
now.
现在
The government has now decided that a large task force will sail,
政府已经决定马上派出 大量军队
as soon as all preparations are complete.
一准备好马上出发
Prime Minister we do still have three weeks before our ships reach the islands.
首相 在军舰到达岛屿之前 还有三周时间
All we’re saying is that we shouldn’t give up on trying to find a diplomatic solution.
我们仍旧认为 不该放弃使用外交手段来解决
The U.S. Secretary of State has arrived, Prime Minister.
美国国务卿到了 首相
So you are proposing to go to war over these Islands.
所以你提议应该发起战争
They’re thousands of miles away, a handful of citizens,
它们在几千英里以外 民众又不多
politically and economically insignificant, if you’ll excuse me.
政治上经济上都是很微不足道的 原谅我直说
Just like Hawaii, I imagine.
就像夏威夷吧 我想
I’m sorry?
你说什么？
1941, when Japan attacked Pearl Harbour.
1941年 日本人袭击了珍珠港
Did America go cap in hand...
美国政府是否脱帽行礼...
and ask Tojo for a peaceful negotiation of terms?
来向东条英机要求和平解决？
Did she turn her back on her own citizens there...
美国是否背弃了她的公民...
because the islands were thousands of miles from mainland United States?
只是因为那些岛屿离内陆 有几千英里远？
No, no, no!
不，没有！
We will stand on principle or we shall not stand at all.
我们应该坚持立场 否则干脆一事无成
But Margaret with all due respect when one has been to war...
玛格丽特，我很尊重你的意见 但一个人如果要发起战争...
With all due respect sir...
我也很尊重你的意见
I have done battle every single day of my life...
我这一生 没有哪天不在战斗
and many men have underestimated me before.
许多人之前都低估了我
This lot seem bound to do the same...
这群人似乎也犯了同样的错误...
but they will rue the day.
他们终会后悔
Now, shall I be mother?
现在该我行主人之仪了
Tea, Al, how do you take your tea? Black or white?
喝茶吧，阿尔 红茶还是白茶？
The Argentinian ship the General Belgrano and her escorts are pursuing...
阿根廷方面的贝尔戈拉诺军舰 以及其护航舰正在接近...
course 273 degrees toward the Argentinian mainland.
航线呈273度角 驶向阿根廷大陆
We are tracking it with our submarine HMS Conqueror.
我们正用S48潜水艇追踪
Is this ship a threat?
这艘船会是威胁吗？
Both of these ships are carrying Exocet missiles, Prime Minister.
这些船都载有反舰导弹
Just yesterday...
就在昨天...
they launched, then aborted an attack inside the exclusion zone.
他们发射了导弹 然后放弃了禁区内的攻击
There is a risk they could try it again.
他们可能还会再这样做
The Belgrano is sailing directly away from the islands.
贝尔戈拉诺战舰正驶离群岛
Can it really be regarded as a threat?
它真的能成为一个威胁？
She’s been changing course continually.
这艘船一直在改变航线
There’s a strong possibility that they’re attempting a pincer movement on our carrier group.
很有可能他们正在试图 夹击我们的航母战斗群
I advise that we engage them:
我建议让他们这样做
hit the Belgrano as a warning to the others. Send them all back to port.
袭击贝尔戈拉诺 也正好警示其他船 让他们全部退回到港口
It’ll play badly internationally. We’ll be seen as aggressors.
这在国际上影响会很不好 我们会被当成侵略者
This will be an escalation, Prime Minister.
战争会升级的 首相
If there is to be an escalation, it’s better that we start it.
倘若战争真要升级 我们也得先动手
It is steaming away, Prime Minister.
它正在开走 首相
Sink it.
击沉它
HMS Sheffield, a Type 42 destroyer,
谢菲尔德战舰（D80） 42型驱逐舰
was attacked and hit late this afternoon by an Argentine missile...
今天下午晚些时候遭到 阿根廷导弹袭击
it is seen as a retaliation for the sinking of the General Belgrano,
似乎是击沉贝尔戈拉诺战舰 之后的报复行动
in which over 300 Argentinian sailors died...
那次袭击中有300多名 阿根廷士兵死亡...
xxx. Latest casualty figures from the Sheffield.
这里有谢菲尔德战舰最新的伤亡数字
I must write to them.
我得给他们写信
Prime Minister?
首相？
The families.
这些家庭
I must write to them...
我必须给他们写信...
xxx
战舰被炸弹和导弹袭击...
Foreign Secretary...
外交秘书...
I’ve just been briefed by Admiral Fieldhouse.
我刚才接到海军总司令部的报告
He told me bluntly that if the Argentinians are prepared and willing to risk their aircraft,
他直截了当地告诉我 如果阿根廷人准备好并愿意牺牲他们的空军
they have enough missiles to cripple most of our fleet.
他们有足够的导弹 消灭我们的船队
President Reagan and President Bellaunde of Peru have
里根总统和贝朗德总统（秘鲁）
some new proposals for the peace plan -
提议了一些新的和平解决方案
The peace plan?
和平解决方案？
There will be no appeasement. This is a war.
不允许有妥协 这是战争
A war they started and by God, we will finish it.
他们发起的战争 有上帝在我们这边 我们要结束它
I tell you what I’m going to write...
我会告诉我将要写的...
to every single one of these families, these heartbroken families?
给每个牺牲的军人的家庭 这些心碎的家庭
I am going to tell them that no British soldier will die in vain...
我会告诉他们 没有一个英国士兵会白白牺牲
for the Falklands.
在这次福克兰群岛的战争里
Lieutenant Colonel Jones. Captain Wood. Captain Dench.
卡罗内尔・琼斯中尉 伍德船长 丹奇船长
I am the only Prime Minister in the history of our country...
我是英国历史上唯一 一任这样的首相...
who is also a mother with a son of my own,
自己本人也是一位母亲 有自己的孩子
I can imagine your agony, and your grief.
你们的痛苦和悲伤 我感同身受
Prime Minister, we have secured the beach head -
首相 我们已经保卫了海滩
The Argentinian troops are demoralized and ill equipped...
阿根廷军队士气低落 装备不全
The paratroops have taken Goose Green...
空降部队拿下了古斯格林镇...
Shortly after dark last night, our forces xxx Port Stanley...
在昨晚天黑后不久 我们在斯坦利港周围的部队...
xxx what the Commander in Chief has called a brilliant surprise night attack.
打了一场好仗 总司令称赞其为漂亮的夜袭
Thatcher, bed.
撒切尔，该睡了
From their new positions, our forces can see large numbers of Argentine soldiers
在新的据点，我们的军队可以看到 大量的阿根廷士兵...
retreating and streaming back into Port Stanley.
正在撤回到斯坦利港里
Our forces are moving forward to exploit their success.
我们的军队正在前进 为扩大胜利
Well done, MARGARET.
干得漂亮 玛格丽特
We congratulate the men and women of the armed Forces for their skill,
我们由衷地祝贺 这次出征的男女士兵
bravery and loyalty to this country.
嘉奖他们娴熟勇敢 且忠诚地报效祖国
We were faced with an act of unprovoked aggression...
我们遭到了无端的侵略...
and we responded as we have responded in times past:
我们也如以往一样回击
with unity, strength and courage,
以我们的团结 力量 和勇气
sure in the knowledge that though much is sacrificed,
我肯定虽然我们作出了很大的牺牲
in the end, right will prevail over wrong.
最终正义将战胜邪恶
And I put it to the Honourable Member opposite...
我要告诉在座尊敬的各位
that this is not a day for him to carp...
今天不应争吵
find fault, demand inquiries-
或是发现问题 调查需求...
they will happen I can assure him of that...
这些以后肯定会被落实
for we have nothing to hide, no...
因为我们没有任何可隐瞒
this is a day to put difference aside,
因为今天我们要同仇敌忾
hold one’s head high...
昂首挺胸地...
and take pride in being British.
为作为一个英国人而自豪
GOTCHA! Well that paid off old girl! Your ratings soared!
吓到你了！ 这下都还清了 你的支持率上去了！
From the most hated Prime Minister of all time to the nation’s darling...
从史上最不受欢迎的首相 到全民爱戴的人...
The world was at your feet, and Britain was back in business!
世界在你脚下 英国回到正轨！
The Berlin Wall has fallen. The gates have opened!
柏林墙已经倒塌 大门敞开了！
The police are making no attempt to stop people as they go through.
警察并没有阻止人们穿过它
I don’t agree... I don’t agree in any measure!
我不同意... 任何标准来衡量我都不同意！
But Prime Minister the question of the European single currency will come up.
但是首相大人 欧洲统一货币的问题就要拿上台面了
I don’t think the country is ready for it yet.
我不认为我们国家 已经准备好这个变化
But we cannot bury our heads in the sand...
但我们总不能像鸵鸟一样把头埋进沙子
A lot of Conservative MP’s and Ministers are saying -
很多保守党议员 和大臣都在说...
- that there must be a change in that style of management.
管理模式必须发生改变
That Mrs Thatcher must listen more, and on occasion, give in.
撒切尔夫人必须听从更多意见 或者有时候，进行妥协
The point is, Prime Minister,
关键是，首相
I don’t think we can sell the idea of a tax that asks everyone to pay the same.
我不认为我们可以将 人人赋税相等这个想法推广
Our policies may be unpopular, but they are the right policies.
我们的政策或许不受欢迎 但它是正确的
Prime Minister I just don’t think we can ask the poorest of the poor...
首相大人 我只是不认为最穷的穷人...
to pay the same amount of tax as a multi-millionaire.
应该和那些百万富翁 赋相同的税
There it is again! Why not?
又来了！ 为什么不？
Because -
因为...
Because people... on the whole... think that the tax is manifestly unfair.
因为大家...整体都认为... 赋税政策显然不平等
Nonsense. Arrant nonsense.
胡说 完全是胡说
This is a simple proposition. In order to live in this country,
这个主张很简单 如果想要生活在这个国家
you must pay for the privilege- something, anything!
就要为自己的权利赋税 不管是什么！
If you pay nothing, you care nothing.
不赋税 就不会关心国家
What do you care where you throw your rubbish?
你怎会关心应该把垃圾扔到哪里
Your council estate is a mess, your town, graffiti, what do you care?
你的政务房产一塌糊涂 你的镇子 你不会关心
It's not your problem, it's somebody else's problem-
这反正不是你的问题 是别人的问题
it's the government's problem!
反正是政府的问题！
Your problem...
你们的问题...
Some of you,
你们之间的一些人
is that you haven't got the courage for this fight.
就是你们没有勇气进行斗争
You haven’t had to fight hard for anything.
你们没有为任何事艰苦斗争过
It's all been given to you- and you feel guilty about it!
一切都是生来就有的... 你们这是感到羞愧！
Well, may I say, on behalf of all those who have had to fight their way up,
我要说的是 代表那些一路斗争走上来的人
and who don't feel guilty about it...
内心毫无愧疚的人...
we resent those slackers who take, take, take...
我们憎恨那些一味 索取 索取 索取的懒鬼
and contribute nothing to the community!
那些对社会毫无贡献的人！
And I see the same thing, the same cowardice...
我也看到了同样的胆怯...
in our fight within the European Union.
在我们和欧盟的抗争中
Cowardice.
怯懦
For the sovereignty of Britain the integrity of the pound!
为了英国的主权 为了英镑的气节！
Some of you want to make concessions.
你们有些人想要做出让步
I hear some of you...
我听说你们有些人...
agree with the latest French proposals.
同意最近法国人的提议...
Well, why don’t you get on a boat to Calais?
你们干嘛不登上去 加莱（法国海港 正对英吉利海峡）的船？
Yes, why don't you put on a beret,
是啊，你们干嘛不戴个贝雷帽
and pay 85% of your income to the French government!
把自己收入的85%交给法国政府！
Right.
好吧
What can we realistically hope to achieve by the end of session, Lord President?
我们这次会议的切实目的是什么 总统阁下？
And why have we not made more progress to date?
我们为何没有把日程安排得更好？
What is that? Is that the timetable?
那是什么？ 是时间表吗？
I haven't seen that. May I see it?
我还没过目 能看看吗？
Here it is, Prime Minister. Of course.
给 首相大人 当然
The wording is sloppy here...
这里用词不好...
and here.
还有这里
If you say so. - I do say so.
- 如果你要这么说的话 - 我就是要这么说
It’s merely a first draft...
这仅仅是个初稿...
This is ridiculous. There are two “T’s” in “committee”!
太荒谬了 “委员会（committee）”里有两个T！
Two “T’s”. This is shameful. Shameful!
有两个T！ 真丢人，太可耻了
I can’t even rely on you for a simple timetable!
这么简单的一个时间表 我都不能信任你们
Are you unwell?
你不舒服吗？
Yes. You are unwell.
是啊 你就是不舒服
Give me the pencil, give it to me!
铅笔给我 给我！
If this is the best you can do I had better send you to hospital,
如果这就是你的最佳状态 那我最好得把你送医院
and I shall do your job as well as my own and everyone else’s.
我得负责我的工作 还有你的 还有所有其他人的
Gentlemen.
先生们
As the Lord President has thosen to come to cabinet unprepared...
因为总统阁下 毫无准备地就来了内阁...
I have to close this meeting.
会议必须结束了
Good morning!
日安！
Can’t pay, won’t pay!
付不起 也不会付！
Geoffrey-
杰弗里...
My letter of resignation.
我的辞职信
Our differences, I’m afraid, cannot be reconciled.
我们意见向左 恐怕无法复合
I have done what I believe to be right for my party and my country.
我正在做自己认为 对国家对政党有利的事
The time has come for others to consider...
现在轮到其他人来考虑...
their own response to the tragic conflict of loyalties...
他们该如何面对 忠诚造成的冲突
with which I have myself wrestled for perhaps too long.
我本人已经斗争了太久
Geoffrey’s speech in the House of Commons was devastating.
杰弗里在下议院的发言 相当有压倒性
He was almost inviting someone to challenge her for leadership of the party.
他这几乎是在邀请其他人 撼动她在政党的领袖地位
She behaved appallingly.
她的表现令人吃惊
I wouldn’t have spoken to my gamekeeper like that.
我可不会对自己的守护者如此说话
I don’t think she can survive this.
我不认为这次她能挺过去
I’m here to announce my decision
我在这里要宣布我的决定
to put my name forward as leader of the Conservative party.
我要参与竞选保守党党魁职务
I have nothing but admiration for our Prime Minister, Margaret Thatcher,
我对时任首相玛格丽特・撒切尔 非常尊敬
but I believe...
但是我相信...
our party and our country need a new leader.
我们的政党和国家 需要新的领导人
It’s extraordinary.
真不可思议
I am the Prime Minister. - The rules of the Conservative Party...
- 我是首相 - 保守党的规则...
make it possible for Conservative MP’s to depose a sitting Prime Minister.
让保守党国会议员 有权免职现任的首相
Sweetie?
吃个糖？
As Conservative MP’s gather in Westminster to discus...
威斯敏斯特的保守党议员决定...
who they will back in the leadership contest, the Prime Minister said...
谁来参与党魁竞争 首相说...
she would not be diverted from critical international affairs.
她不会从重要的国际事务 转移注意力
Tonight in Paris Mrs Thatcher is among thirty four world leaders
今天晚上于巴黎 撒切尔夫人 和34位世界各国领导人
who came together to celebrate the end of the Cold War and herald...
大家齐聚一堂庆祝冷战的结束
the start of a peaceful new age of East/West cooperation.
欢庆东西方合作的 和平新时代的到来
There’s a general feeling that Mrs Thatcher is going to win on the first ballot.
大家都认为撒切尔夫人 会赢得第一次票选
We’re going to put it to bed tomorrow night, is how one of her campaign staff puts it.
明晚就会产生结果 她的竞选工作人员如是说
M, I really think you should come home and defend yourself old girl.
玛格丽特我真的觉得你应该回家来 为自己辩护
Heseltine is campaigning ferociously.
赫塞尔廷的竞选攻势很猛烈
I do think my time is best spent seeing an end to the Cold War...
我认为我现在应该做的事 是目睹冷战的结束...
don’t you? After all this time they know what I stand for.
你不这么觉得吗？ 这么长时间以来他们知道我的立场
Will she, or will she not, be in the job tomorrow?
她到底会不会 明天还是首相？
Margaret, they can’t touch you.
玛格丽特，他们不能撼动你
Mrs Thatcher has failed to win enough votes to secure an outright...
撒切尔夫人在投票中 没能赢得足够多的选票...
win in the leadership contest and must now decide...
来直接赢得这次选举 现在她必须决定...
whether to put her name forward for the second round.
是否参加第二轮投票
As Mrs Thatcher leaves Paris for London to make a last ditch attempt...
撒切尔夫人正从巴黎赶回伦敦 来作最后一搏...
to pull together support for her leadership, the ship may have sailed.
汇集所有支持她的人 竞选就要开始了
Treachery!
背信弃义！
We will never win another election led by that woman.
下次大选如果还是她领导 我们不可能赢
We need a leader who listens.
我们需要一个听得进意见的领导人
This isn’t about her, it’s about the party.
不是针对她 是关于整个党
One must know when to go.
一个人必须知道 什么时候该放手
The question is, how does anyone put it to her?
问题是 谁来告诉她这些？
If you were to stand, I of course would vote for you Prime Minister-
如果您要奋起竞选 我当然会投您的票 首相...
of course would vote for you Prime Minister, but I don’t think you can win.
我当然会为你投票 但我不认为你可以赢
The loyalty of my colleagues cannot be counted upon.
我的同事们他们的忠诚度 并不算数
It was the people who put me here -
是你们让我做到这个位置...
The loyalty of my colleagues cannot be counted upon.
我的同事们 他们的忠诚度并不算数
- it’s up to them to tell me when to go.
由他们决定我的去留吧
Margaret, you can’t let them do this to you.
玛格丽特 你不能让他们对你这样做
Please, boss.
拜托了
They’ll destroy you. Throw in the towel now, love.
他们会毁了你的 现在就认输吧 亲爱的
Don’t let those bastards see you humiliated.
不要让这些混蛋们 看着你被羞辱
You just won’t win, darling. Not this time.
你只是没有赢而已 亲爱的 就这一次
Oh Denis.
噢 丹尼斯
I am the Prime Minister.
我是首相
Order! Order!
肃静 肃静！
The Right Honourable gentleman is afraid!
尊敬的在座各位 你们害怕了！
This is a naked strategy of closing some coal mines...
这是赤裸裸的阴谋 来关闭一些煤矿...
and then selling off. - They believe in striking...
- 然后卖掉它们 - 他们坚持罢工...
I believe in working! - This is the woman who’s watched...
- 而我坚信的是工作！ - 这个女人亲眼目睹了...
ten men on hunger strike starve themselves to death and never flinched!
10名工人因为绝食罢工而饿死 但毫无退却！
Despicable.
卑鄙
More homeowners, more shareholders, more savings -
更多的房主 更多的股东 更多的存款...
I offer my resignation...
我要发表辞职声明...
after eleven and a half extraordinary years -
在不可思议的11年任期之后...
proud to have left Britain in a much better state...
我很自豪英国的状况有了很大改善
than when we took office.
相比起我接管的时候
What’s this then?
这是什么？
A radio...
收音机...
How useful.
非常有用
Steady, MT.
稳住了 玛格丽特
The greatest Prime Minister since Churchill...
自丘吉尔以来最伟大的首相...
deposed by a bunch of spineless pygmies!
被一群没骨气的矮子罢黜了！
All those years of taking the tough decisions...
那么多充满着艰难决定的年头...
does any of it matter now?
现在还有什么意义呢？
It’s all been turned to mush!
都不算数了！
What? - By these fools!
- 什么？ - 被这些蠢材！
These lily-livered pinkos!
这些胆小鬼！
These inept placators. - Very good! These vacillators.
- 这些无能的墙头草 - 对！这些墙头草！
Vacillators! Poll takers. - Popularity seekers.
- 墙头草！见风使舵！ - 追名逐利
So busy taking the pulse of the public!
整天忙着迎合别人！
Weak. Is weak.
软弱 这是软弱
Weak... - All off them. Weak.
软弱... - 他们都太软弱
Men!
男人啊！
Don’t they know if you take the tough decisions.
他们不知道你是否 做了任何艰难的决定
Yes, people will hate you today but they’ll thank you for generations.
是的 今天人们是恨你的 但世世代代的人们会感谢你
Or forget you entirely and chuck you out with the rubbish!
亦或是把你彻底遗忘 像垃圾一样倒掉！
All I wanted was to make a difference in the world.
我只是想要 改变这个世界
And you did, love, you did.
你做到了 亲爱的 你做到了
All I wanted was for my children to grow up well and be happy...
我只是想要我的孩子们 健康快乐地成长...
happier than I was certainly.
当然 要比我快乐
xxx
我这些都留着...
Oh, yes.
在这儿呢
And I wanted you to be happy of course.
我当然希望你也能快乐
Were you happy, Denis?
你快乐吗 丹尼斯？
Tell me the truth.
跟我说实话
Denis?
丹尼斯？
Here’s your bag. You’re all packed, sorted.
这是你的包 都打包好了 分类好了
Denis wait. Where are your shoes?
丹尼斯 等等 你的鞋呢？
No, you can’t go without shoes!
不 你不能不穿鞋就走！
Not yet. - Steady.
- 还不行 - 别慌
Yes. Steady.
是啊 冷静
Steady the buffs. - Steady the buffs.
- 冷静 稳住 - 冷静 稳住...
No. Not yet. Denis.
不 还不行 丹尼斯
Wait...
等等...
I don’t, I cant. I don’t want you to go yet.
我不 我不能... 我还不想让你走
Denis. Please.
丹尼斯 求你了
No, no. You are not.
不 不 你不能走...
I don’t want to be on my own.
我不想自己一个人
You’re going to be fine on your own, love. You always have been.
你一个人能很好的 亲爱的 你一直如此
Denis!
丹尼斯！
xxx
不，不，不……
Mummy-
妈妈...
My God, Mum. Are you alright?
天哪 妈妈 你没事吧？
Yes. - What are you doing.
- 恩 - 你这是怎么了？
Mummy you should have called for help, silly old sausage.
妈妈你应该叫人来帮忙的 真是老糊涂啦
Have you not even been in your bed properly?
你甚至都没好好睡下吗？
You’ve done all this? - Yes, all sorted.
- 你一个人做的？ - 是的 都分类好了
Well don’t worry about all this. June and I will crack on with it.
不用担心这些 琼和我会办好的
I was just going to get dressed.
我正要去穿衣服
Shall I call someone, see if anyone can come over and do your hair?
我该叫别人来 帮你做头发吗？
Oh. No, you do it.
噢，不 你来就行了
Oh, let me do that, Margaret.
噢，我来吧 玛格丽特
No, dear, I’ll do it.
不 亲爱的 我可以
Carol said you might go to the House of Lords today?
卡萝尔说今天您可能 会去上议院？
No no. I’m not going anywhere.
不，不 我哪里都不去